Janice Terpin Johnson

0

484-744-2643

0

jmtj.johnson@gmail.com

(in)

LinkedIn-janicejohnson

FuturePortfolio.com

EDUCATION

Career Foundry

UX Design

University of Notre Dame

BBS, Management Information Systems

HARD SKILLS

User Research

User Personas

Prototyping

Wireframes

User Testing

Web Design

Presentations

Digital Data Analytics

Digital Marketing

SOFT SKILLS

Effective Communication

Leadership & Collaboration

Empathy

Human Center Design

Problem Solving

Critical Thinking

TOOLS

Figma Adobe Analytics Adobe Creative Suite Marvel HTML/CSS

PROFILE

UX Designer - Passionate about continuous improvement

I am passionate about applying my previous digital data and marketing experience with my creativity, empathy, and solution-finding mindset into my work. I continuously seek to create better user experiences for everyone, everywhere.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

January 2017 - April 2022

Digital Data Leader

Vanguard, Malvern, PA

- Lead development of integrated Campaign Meta Data systems across channels and operating systems, allowing analysts easier access to deeper insights for two divisions.
- Created strategy and led development of integrated dashboards to enable department members and business partners to easily access insights to marketing qualified leads and to make data-driven decisions.
- Developed strategy and led the execution of a tailored curriculum for the department's Analytical Learning & Development program to increase analytical acumen, including Test & Learn Class, Adobe Analytics Workshop, Foundational & Insights Dashboards Workshops, and weekly Office Hours.

November 2015 to June 2016

Solutions Consultant

Lima Consulting Group

Partnered with clients to deliver analytics, SEO, and campaign implementation. Responsibilities included creating analysis and insights reports with recommendations of content to publish based on research, seasonality, and past results; developing and implementing inbound marketing campaigns to attract potential clients.

July 2016 to January 2017

Digital Marketing Consultant

Wunderman

Led global email team executing 40-70 deliveries per week in multiple languages for a global travel industry leader using Adobe Campaign.

November 2013 to October 2015

Digital Marketing Specialist

KBM Group

Managed multiple clients' email marketing campaigns. Responsibilities included writing HTML for email, creating and implementing test campaigns, and managing live deployments.

- Reverse-engineered a new client's existing Responsys campaign for deployment and
 established more efficient methods for future campaigns. There was no
 documentation on how the complex campaign initially functioned. The campaign
 used over 90 driving HTML templates to display 200+ monthly offer modules across 5
 languages and was driven by a distribution list of over 8 million records.
- Transformed the campaign process with a design team to reduce the number of templates to 8 and still accommodate the 5 languages and 200+ offer modules using supplemental tables and dynamic content. Converted client's campaign from Responsys 5 to 6.

Certifications

Adobe Certified Expert Analytics Business Practitioner Adobe Certified Expert Campaign Business Practitioner HubSpot Inbound Marketing seoClarity Certified User January 2009 to August 2013

Email Campaign Strategist

SEI

Executed advanced email campaign planning and operations; implemented email best practices; ensured clear content and layout; resolved application issues; provided support and training for each of the business units; HTML and basic Photoshop editing.

Managed the marketing email service application, Responsys, for SEI Corporate and its 5 business groups across a global market.